Contact

bearrn@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/gregory-c-bearinger-477154152 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation (CPR)

TNCC

Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS)

Certifications

Nurse Executive Board Certified

National Healthcare Disaster Professional (NHDP-BC)

Certified Trauma Registered Nurse

Certified Emergency Nurse

Honors-Awards

SALUTE

Phi Theta Kappra

Honor Society

Gregory C. Bearinger

MSN, RN, CEN, TCRN, NHDP-BC, NE-BC

Houston, Texas Area

Summary

I am a seasoned nurse clinician and manager as well as a freshly minted healthcare leadership & administration graduate from the University of Texas Arlington with 27+ years of operations leadership and patient care experience in the emergency medicine arena. Recognized for demonstrating a natural aptitude for workflow optimization, as well as for maintaining records management systems and evaluating personnel, I have a history of contributing to clinic growth and expansion throughout my career. Professional focal points include clinical data analysis, operational optimization, care quality assessment, multicultural inclusion, recruitment & hiring, management development, compliance assurance, community engagement, records management, analytical reporting, financial administration, technology solutions, and client relationship management. Delivering superior administration on the latter areas of expertise requires utilization of effective communication skills, and resource management to support efficiency and maximum returns.

Currently, I am the Nurse Clinician 5, Emergency Services with UTMB Angleton Campus. Under my leadership, I apply advanced nursing and clinical skills to evaluate, plan, and execute appropriate patient care in emergency situations. I liaise with senior leadership, external care providers, and nursing teams to ensure the campus's operational support structure is driving superior clinical practice with minimal expenditures.

Colleagues describe me as a progressive, driven, down-to-earth, analytical and managerial expert who can be relied on to offer superior solutions that deliver efficient results on time and under budget.

I am pursuing new opportunities and can be reached through this profile, or by phone at 919-801-8319

Experience

The University of Texas Medical Branch MSN, RN, CEN, TCRN, NHDP-BC, NE-BC February 2017 - July 2019 (2 years 6 months) Angleton, TX

HCA Gulf Coast Division

3 years 6 months

ED Nurse Manager

October 2015 - June 2016 (9 months)

Pearland Medical Center

- Built and maintained computerized record management systems to store and process data such as personnel activities and information, as well as to produce reports.
- Delegated, oversaw and evaluated work activities of medical, nursing, technical, clerical, service, maintenance, and other personnel to ensure the highest quality of care and streamlined workflow.

ED Nurse Manager

November 2014 - October 2015 (1 year)

Kingwood Medical Center

- Produced activity reports informing management of the status and implementation plans of programs, services, and quality initiatives.
- Orchestrated work schedules and assignments for staff according to workload, space, and equipment availability. Hiring and training of new employees.

ED Nurse Manager

January 2013 - November 2014 (1 year 11 months)

Clear Lake Medical Center

- Steered recruitment and hiring activities as well as trained personnel.
- Governed and assessed work activities of medical, nursing, technical, clerical, service, maintenance, and other personnel.
- Shepard the successful transition from a designated level 3 trauma center to a level 2 designated trauma center.

Granville Health System Patient Care Coordinator

April 2000 - December 2012 (12 years 9 months) Oxford, NC

- Supervised medical, nursing, technical, clerical, service, maintenance, and other staff by scheduling and evaluating daily activities.
- Devised, initiated, and regulated programs and services in the medical facility, including personnel administration, training, and coordination of medical, nursing and physical plant staff.

Duke University Health System
Hyperbaric Nurse
May 2003 - June 2005 (2 years 2 months)
Durham, NC

• Recorded and organized data related to patients' care including assessment results, interventions, medications, patient responses, or treatment changes.

Learning Services
Residential Manager
September 1999 - March 2000 (7 months)
Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina Area

- Executed and administered fiscal operations, including accounting, planning budgets, authorizing expenditures, establishing rates for services, and coordinating financial reporting.
- Coordinated activities of medical, nursing, technical, clerical, service, maintenance, and other personnel and evaluated performance.

New Jersey Training School for Boys Head Nurse August 1993 - February 1996 (2 years 7 months) Patterson, NJ

Helene Fuld Medical Center Staff Registered Nurse June 1991 - August 1994 (3 years 3 months) Trenton, NJ

US Navy
Petty Officer Third Class
July 1984 - July 1991 (7 years 1 month)

Education

The University of Texas at Arlington MSN July 2018 · (2017 - 2018)

San Jacinto College
Associate in Liberal Arts · (2015 - 2016)

The University of Texas at Arlington
BSN, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2015 - 2016)

Helene Fuld Medical Center School of Nursing
Diploma in Nursing (3-year), Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (1989 - 1991)

Mercer County Community College
Associate of Science - AS, Nursing Education · (1989 - 1991)